Guide to the Victor S. Navasky Papers TAM.594
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Personal and Biographical Material, 1939-2012
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Acceptance letter, Apr 1950 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Meeting Materials, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Meeting Materials, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Meeting Materials, 1991, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Meeting Materials, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Meeting Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Meeting Materials, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers Profiles, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Board of Managers' Nominating Committee Meeting Materials, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Class Notes, 1952, 1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Class Notes, 1954, 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Class Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Essay Fragments, 1953, 1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Essays, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Essays, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Essays, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Essays, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Exams, May 1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Exams, May 1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: "The Flit", May 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: General, 1959, 1995, 1997, 2003-2005, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: "Karoso", 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: "The Lit", Feb 1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Professorship materials, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Reunion, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Scrapbook, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Semester in Washington, Jan 1953-Jan 1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: "Swarthmore College Bulletin", 1958, 1984, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: "Swarthmore College Bulletin" Article, Dec 1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Education: Swarthmore College - Swarthmore Phoenix, Oct 1950-Apr 1954 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Thesis, May 1954 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Thesis Research, Nov 1953-Jul 1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: Transcript (copy), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Education: Swarthmore College: (includes correspondence such as acceptance letters, Phi Beta Kappa membership...), 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Education: The University of Chicago Law School, Jul 1955, Jan 1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Education: Yale Law School: "Connecticut Civil Liberties" Newsletter, Dec 1957, May 1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Essay: "The Benevolent Housing Quota", Jun 1955-Jul 1955, Jan 1960 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Essay: "Deportation as Punishment" (in Kansas City Law Review), 1953-1954, 1958-1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Essay - "Studies in Political Man: Two Hungarian Portraits" (includes related material), 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Essays, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Essays, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Exams, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Fred Rodell Articles, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Education: Yale Law School: General (includes correspondence), 1956, 1957, 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Education: Yale Law School: "Politics and the Law School" by Gaddis Smith, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Reunion, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Education: Yale Law School: Transcipt and student data sheet, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Education: Yale Law School: "Yale Law Report" (contributor), 1959, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Education: Yale Law School: "Yale Daily News" - "Allen Ginsberg Reads Poetry", Nov 1958 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Family: Navasky, Anne (includes audio C.D. "Mother's Day Mix"), 2006, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Family: Navasky, Bruno, 1980, Jul 2005 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Family: Navasky, Esther, 1939, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Family: Navasky, Macy, 1988, 1989, 2005, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Family: Navasky, Miri, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Family: Ration books, circa 1943, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Family: Various items, 1972-1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - G. Mennen Williams Material (Williams was Michigan Governor 1949-1961; Navasky, an assistant 1959-1961), 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Health, 2010, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Health: Arthritis - General, 1953-1956, 1970-1972, 1982-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Health: Arthritis - Travel, 1984, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Health: Arthritis - Travel, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Health: Sharks Don't Get Cancer by Dr. I William Lane and Linda Comac, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Invitation to Inauguration of John F. Kennedy, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Letterhead, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Military: "53rd Infantry News", Aug 1955-May 1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Military: "Alaska Nugget", May 1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Military: "Anchorage News", 1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Military: Education and Training Allowance, Sep 1957-May 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Military: General (includes correspondence), Dec 1954-Jul 1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Military: Letter of Commendation, Jun 1956 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Military: Navasky correspondence with publishers, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Military: Photograph, Company D - 3rd Batallion Medical Training Center Fort Sam Houston, TX, Jan 7, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Military: Publications, Feb 1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Military: Veterans Administration (includes correspondence), Nov 1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Military: Writings, circa 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Personal Items: Various, 1959, 2005, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Personal Items: Various (watermelon sale posters), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Photographs, 1954, 1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Photographs: Macy and Esther Navasky (includes related correspondence), 1962, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ramsey Clark campaign clippings (includes letter from Merle Miller), 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Rolodex, undated (Box 30)
  - Early Writings and Personal Correspondence, 1954-1966 (Box 110)
- Series II: Navasky and The Nation, 1902-2015
  - Subseries IIA: Early History
    This subseries is arranged with other Nation materials as it provides a look at the magazine's early (pre-Navasky) years. It is likely, however, that its content was gathered as research for Navasky's book, A Matter of Opinion, which devotes much attention to the history of The Nation.
    Highlights of this material include correspondence (mostly photocopies) associated with previous Nation editors and publishers and involving such notables as Clarence Darrow, Albert Einstein, Fiorello LaGuardia, John Maynard Keynes, Franklin and Theodore Roosevelt, Stephen Spender, Theodore Dreiser, Sinclair Lewis, and Adolf Hitler. There are also editorial memos; the unfinished draft of a book being written by Freda Kirchway, "The Nation – 1918 to 1958, Outline of a Book"; a variety of articles and speeches; the transcript of an oral history by Carey McWilliams; and a 1939 survey of The Nation subscribers conducted by Elmo Roper. Materials concerning The Nation's financial history are also of interest.
    - "Changing Editorships" - McWilliams, Kirchwey, 1919, 1951-1955, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Copies of memoranda, correspondence, statements re: Editors and Publishers (includes Villard, Wertheim, Kirchwey, Storrow, McWilliams), 1936-1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Various, 1949-1952, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Editorial Memos: Staff (including Villard, Kirchwey, McWilliams and others), 1919-1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Editorial Memos: Staff (including Villard, Kirchwey, McWilliams and others), 1942-1953 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Editorial Memos: Staff (including Villard, Kirchwey, McWilliams and others), 1951-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Eisenhower Letter-Publicity" (re: Soviet sponsored Anti-Semitism), 1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Finance: "Program for 'The Nation' A Prospectus", 1951, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Finance: "Program for 'The Nation' A Prospectus" (Drafts), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Finance: "Subject: The Nation Problems and Program" (Memorandum to Freda Kirchwey), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Financial History, 1942-1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Financial History, 1966-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - General History, 1940-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - General History: Newspaper Clippings, 1937-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Kirchwey, Freda: Correspondence (includes copies of letters from Clare Boothe Luce and Thomas Mann), 1943-1954, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Kirchwey, Freda: Libel Suit (The Nation against The New Leader and Clement Greenberg), 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Kirchwey, Freda: "The Nation--1918 to 1958, Outline of a Book" (unfinished draft), undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Korea-Memoranda", 1957 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Letters to the Editor: Copies of letters from Adolf Hitler and Stephen Spender (and associated material), 1925, 1951, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - McWilliams, Carey, 1960-1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - McWilliams, Carey, 1972-1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Articles and speeches, 1951-1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Articles and speeches, 1956-1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Bibliography of published writings and of books, 1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Book project to commemorate McWilliams (Festschrift), 1975-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence (includes letters from Norman Corwin), 1952-1979, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence (exchange among McWilliams, Tom Hayden, Stanley Sheinbaum RE: John Anderson), 1979, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence (includes letters from Rose Russell and Otto Nathan), 1948-1981 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence and articles re: Assassinations (includes letter from Congressman Henry B. Gonzalez), 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence and articles re: Time Magazine, 1956-1968 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence to Freda Kirchwey, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Correspondence with James Storrow, 1965-1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Editorial Project (includes letter from Wallace Stegner), 1957 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - McWilliams, Carey: "Honorable in All Things" Interview transcript, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Notes, 1975, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - McWilliams, Carey: Oral history transcript, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - "Mentions of Nation articles, editors, writers", 1925, 1939, 1951, 1971, 1985, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Nation Associates, 1949, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Nation banned in New York City public school libraries, 1949-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - The Nation NOT soft on Communism: List of articles, circa 1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Storrow, James J.: Memorial Service, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Storrow, James J.: Personal Correspondence, 1971, 1976, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Storrow, James J. Files, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Storrow, James J. Files, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Storrow, James J. Files, 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Storrow, James J. Files: Articles, newspaper clippings on a wide variety of topics, 1960s, 1970s, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Storrow, James J. Files: Carey McWilliams' employment agreement and related materials, 1956-1966, 1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Storrow, James J. Files: Carey McWilliams' resignation, 1975-1976, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Storrow, James J. Files: Reports submitted by Carey McWilliams, 1958-Aug 1, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Storrow, James J. Files: Reports submitted by Carey McWilliams, Aug 1, 1962-Sep 1, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Storrow, James J. Files: Reports submitted by Carey McWilliams, Sep 1, 1964-Sep 1, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "A Study Conducted Among 978 Subscribers of The Nation" Elmo Roper, Aug 1939 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) - Beard, Charles, 1922-1946 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) - B-D (includes letters from Hodding Carter, Clarence Darrow, Theodore Dreiser and John Foster Dulles, 1915-1946 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) - Einstein, Albert (German), 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) E-G (includes letters from Felix Frankfurter and Ernest Greuning), 1907-1941 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) H-L (includes letters from Cordell Hull, John Maynard Keynes, Fiorello Laguardia and Sinclair Lewis), 1929-1945 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) M-R (includes letters from H.L. Mencken and Syngman Rhee), 1907-1948 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1914-1940 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1902-1903 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison: Correspondence (copies) S-W (includes letter from Margaret Sanger), 1915-1943 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Subseries IIB: Navasky as Editor, 1978-1995
    This subseries focuses on the period of Navasky's editorship of The Nation under publishers Hamilton Fish and Arthur Carter. As with the initial Nation subseries, much of its content may have been collected for A Matter of Opinion. There are agreements and contracts, as well as correspondence; material concerning the magazine's operation, including personnel issues; and a selection of press clippings during that period (1978-1995).
    - Agreement to purchase assets between Nation Enterprises and The Nation Company Inc., 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Agreement to purchase assets between Nation Enterprises and The Nation Company Inc.: Drafts, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Agreement to purchase assets between Nation Enterprises and The Nation Company Inc.: Drafts (Exhibits), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Agreement to purchase assets between Nation Enterprises and The Nation Company Inc.: Exhibits B and C, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Carter, Arthur, 1986, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Carter Materials", 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Carter Materials", 1987-1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Carter Materials": Notes and fragments, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Cockburn, Alexander: Issues (includes letter from Elie Wiesel), 1986-1993, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Consolidation/Conglomeration", 1976-1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Contracts and agreements: Various, 1985-1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence (includes letters from Molly Ivins and Aryeh Neier), 1979-1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Fish, Hamilton: Materials related to 1977 option agreement to purchase The Nation (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Kirchwey, Freda: Obituary, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - The Nation Book Club: Draft proposal, circa 1992 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - The Nation critique, 1977-1988, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - The Nation enterprises, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Nation-Getting There", 1976, 1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - The Nation purchase "Story" and terms, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - The Nation shareholders, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - The New Statesman, 1986-1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - The Newspaper Guild: 1989 Mediation, related materials, 1988-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Organizational and Personnel Issues: Correspondence, Memos, Notes, 1979-1993, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Potential Merger with The New Republic, 1952, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Press clips, "Best of '78-95", 1978-1993, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Storrow, James J.: Correspondence critical of The Nation and Fish/Navasky agreement, 1982, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IIC: Navasky Becomes Publisher, 1995-2005
    This subseries has as its focus Navasky's purchase of The Nation and his preparation for taking over as publisher. There are memoranda, financial statements, and documents related to the actual purchase; however, the bulk of the material consists of Navasky's "New Nation" file, much of which is centered on potential investors and ideas for a relaunched Nation.
    - Articles regarding the sale of The Nation, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Draft memorandum on The Nation (Freedom Forum Media Studies Center), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Draft memorandum on The Nation (Institute of Politics), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Employment agreements - Navasky, 1985, circa 1994 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Nation Company Inc. financial statements March 31, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Nation Company, L.P. memorandum, Dec 24, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - The Nation packet for potential advertisers (includes 1992 subcriber story), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - The Nation "Private Placement Memorandum", Mar 30, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - The Nation "Private Placement Memorandum": Subscription booklet, Mar 30, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - The Nation "Private Placement Memorandum": Subscription booklet- mended, May 11, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "The Nation November 1994 Projections, Assumptions on Which They are Based" (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - The Nation re: Prospectus, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "New Nation" File: Allina, Franz, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "New Nation" File: Ayers, Brandt, 1986, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "New Nation" File: Anselo, Rene, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "New Nation" File: Brewster, David, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "New Nation" File: Bullitt, Stimson (and Linda Feldman), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "New Nation" File: Bunzl, Martin, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "New Nation" File: California names and addresses, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "New Nation" File: CD-ROM (Nation), 1994 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "New Nation" File: Cohen, Ben, 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "New Nation" File: Cohn, Sam, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "New Nation" File: Corn, David, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - "New Nation" File: Dubow, Aurthur, 1986-1994 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - "New Nation" File: Ellsworth, Whitney, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - "New Nation" File: Elson, Edward, 1984-1994 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - "New Nation" File: Epstein, Howard, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "New Nation" File: Fulton, Katherine, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "New Nation" File: Funabashi, Yoichi, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "New Nation" File: Guber, Peter, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "New Nation" File: Halperin, Lee, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "New Nation" File: Harding, Deborah, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "New Nation" File: Gelber, David, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "New Nation" File: Greene, Wade, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "New Nation" File: Hefner, Christie, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "New Nation" File: Hunter, David, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "New Nation" File: Ingram, Tom, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - "New Nation" File: Lear, Norman, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "New Nation" File: Lerer, Kenneth, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - "New Nation" File: Loy, Frank, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - "New Nation" File: Karoff, Peter/TPI, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - "New Nation" File: Kenan, Amos, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - "New Nation" File: Kobak, James, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - "New Nation" File: Kobaker, Arthur, 1988-1994 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - "New Nation" File: Kovler, Peter, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - "New Nation" File: Mander, Jerry, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "New Nation" File: Mankiewicz, John, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "New Nation" File: McCormac, Win, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "New Nation" File: Memo Comments '94, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "New Nation" File: Millard, Peter, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "New Nation" File: Menschel, Robert, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "New Nation" File: Miller, Ken, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "New Nation" File: Moose, Ed, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "New Nation" File: Morgan, Dodge, 1986-1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "New Nation" File: Morgan, Kim, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "New Nation" File: The Nation direct mail materials, 1988-1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "New Nation" File: The Nation lease, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "New Nation" File: The Nation On-line, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "New Nation" File: Neigher, Alan, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "New Nation" File: New Information Superhighway, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "New Nation" File: Newman, Paul, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "New Nation" File: O'Connor, Carroll, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "New Nation" File: Palmieri, Victor, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "New Nation" File: Perrota, David, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "New Nation" File: Piel, Gerard, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "New Nation" File: Pincus, Lionel, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - "New Nation" File: Potential investors (miscellaneous), undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "New Nation" File: Price, Sol, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "New Nation" File: Relaunched Nation: Business, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "New Nation" File: Rubin, Miles, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - "New Nation" File: Scheer, Robert, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - "New Nation" File: Scheuer, Jeff, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - "New Nation" File: Schulman, Grace, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - "New Nation" File: Skene, Neil, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "New Nation" File: Sheinbaum, Stanley, 1987, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "New Nation" File: Squires, Jim, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - "New Nation" File: Stack, Theresa, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "New Nation" File: Steel, Lewis, undated (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - "New Nation" File: Stone, Oliver, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - "New Nation" File: Streisand, Barbara, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - "New Nation" File: Strongin, Landry, 1994, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - "New Nation" File: Swarthmore potential investors file, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "New Nation" File: Tankersley, Bazy McCormick, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - "New Nation" File: Utne Reader list of visionaries, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - "New Nation" File: Westbrook, Hugh, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - "New Nation" File: Worker ownership, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "New Nation" File: Vanden Heuvel, Katrina, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 42)